<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>My (currently quite boring) Blog</title><link href="/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="/feeds/all.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>/</id><updated>2016-06-12T23:00:00+00:00</updated><entry><title>Introduction</title><link href="/introduction.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2016-06-12T23:00:00+00:00</published><author><name>Ashley Setter</name></author><id>tag:,2016-06-12:introduction.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Hello world!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am Ashley, a Physics graduate and PhD student in the Centre for Doctoral Training for Next Generation Computational Modelling and in the Quantum, Light and Matter group at the University of Southampton. I am interested in programming, physics and all sorts of stuff.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I regularly program in Python, C and C++ for work and for fun! I also, as part of my PhD, programme hardware (namely FPGAs [Field Programmable Gate Arrays]) using VHDL and Verilog. My PhD is in experimental Quantum Physics, in particular I am working in the field of levitated Optomechanics, which basically means particles levitated with lasers; cool, right?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My PhD is looking at ways to control these levitated particles by altering properties of the laser. Currently I am in the process of learning the theory behind DSP (Digital Signal Processing) in order to implement a programme on the FPGA which will modulate the laser power in response to how the levitated particle moves. By doing this in a particular way I should be able to 'cool down' the particle, by this I mean slow down its oscillation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anyway, enough about my PhD, I'm writing this blog for a number of reasons:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;To keep a record of my thoughts during my PhD and what I'm working on&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;To communicate what a physics PhD student does all day&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;To give some helpful tips and even more helpful links for those wanting to learn programming&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;To talk about FPGA programming using HDLs (Hardware Description Languages)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Because I felt like it&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Disclaimer: I'm pretty much doing this on a whim and have no idea if I will continue writing this or if I'll forget it exists tommorrow. Hopefully It will continue!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Well thanks for reading this! I'll maybe expand it to talk more about my other interests and things. If anyone wants me to talk about anything in particular in this blog feel free to leave a comment below.&lt;/p&gt;</summary></entry></feed>